### ARTEM PONOMARENKO

**✓** slfdstrctd@yandex.ru

in linkedin.com/in/slfdstrctd

**▼** t.me/selfdestructed

Specialized in data analysis, machine learning, big data, and AI. Experienced in building optimizing data pipelines, and integrating advanced analytics. Strong background in Python, SQL, PySpark, ML and cloud-based solutions, with a track record of impactful projects in user profiling and forecasting.

### Skills

Languages Python, SQL, R

ML & DS CatBoost, PyTorch, Scikit-learn, MLflow, DVC, A/B testing

Big Data Spark, Hadoop, YTsaurus, Airflow Databases ClickHouse, PostgreSQL, SQLAlchemy

Tools Docker, Kubernetes, FastAPI, CI/CD, Git, Bash

# Experience

VK Nov 2023 - Present

Data Analyst

- Improved user profiling system by integrating new data sources and developing preprocessing pipelines, resulting in a 2x increase in identifier coverage and improved cross-service user matching across VK, OK, Dzen and more.
- Acquired and integrated high-quality geolocation data from Spherum to benchmark and evaluate the
  accuracy of various geolocation tools, enhancing the reliability of location-based analytics.
- Designed and built from scratch the age prediction pipeline for VK profiles, resulting in a highly accurate age prediction model and improving user profiling accuracy by 25%.

### CRPT (Chestny Znak)

Sep 2022 - Nov 2023

Data Analyst

- Developed a time series forecasting model using Prophet to predict digital marking code demand, achieving 4% MAPE improvement and optimizing the national product tracking system's capacity planning.
- Designed and implemented automated data quality monitoring system using Redash and Airflow.
- Optimized reports and queries from BI analysts and crafted data visualizations in Redash to effectively communicate insights.

# **Projects**

JobMatch for HR Luna Park 🔾 — LLM, LoRa, Prompt Engineering

• Fine-tuned LLMs using LoRa and few-shot prompting to match CVs with job descriptions for improved candidate-job alignment.

Salary prediction based on resume for rabota.ru 🗘 — CatBoost, Scikit-learn, MLFlow, DVC

• Engineered features, conducted EDA, and improved salary prediction accuracy by clustering jobs based on skills and training CatBoost models for each cluster.

Smatched (makeup transfer with Stable Diffusion) • PyTorch, Transformers

• Developed a deep learning pipeline for realistic makeup style transfer using Stable Diffusion, enhancing visual fidelity through model fine-tuning and advanced data augmentation.

## Education

#### Saint Petersburg State University

2018 - 2022

Bachelor of Science in Applied Mathematics and Computer Science